{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"A pride","incorrectAnswers":["A muster","A clowder","A shrewdness"],"question":"What is the word for a group of lions?","difficulty":"easy"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"Hindi","incorrectAnswers":["Punjabi","Tamil","Sanskrit"],"question":"Along with English, which other language is an official language of India?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"Pascal","incorrectAnswers":["Borland","Newton","Ohm"],"question":"Name The SI Unit Of Pressure","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Oceania","incorrectAnswers":["South America","Europe","Asia"],"question":"The country of Kiribati is on which continent?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"history","correctAnswer":"John F Kennedy ","incorrectAnswers":["Martin Luther King","Malcolm X","Lee Harvey Oswald"],"question":"Who was assassinated on Nov. 22, 1963? ","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"food_and_drink","correctAnswer":"Gruyere","incorrectAnswers":["Feta","Cheddar","Mozzarella"],"question":"What type of cheese is used to make a classic French Quiche Lorraine?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"Jane Austen","incorrectAnswers":["Percy Bysshe Shelley","Stephenie Meyer","Robert Louis Stevenson"],"question":"Which author wrote 'Pride and Prejudice'?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"Superman","incorrectAnswers":["Transcendant","Evolvee","Final Form"],"question":"What is Friedrich Nietzsche's term for a person who has risen above their passions?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"Today I Learned","incorrectAnswers":["Total Internet Legend","Totally In Love","To Invoke Laughter"],"question":"On internet chats, what do the letters 'TIL' mean?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"Afroasiatic","incorrectAnswers":["Niger–Congo","Sino-Tibetan","Austronesian"],"question":"The language 'Hausa' belongs to which language family?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"Lacoste","incorrectAnswers":["American Airlines","Peugeot","Swarovski"],"question":"Which of these brands has a crocodile on its logo?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Yerevan","incorrectAnswers":["Khartoum","Vilnius","Vaduz"],"question":"What is the capital city of Armenia?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"Dustin Hoffman","incorrectAnswers":["Dan Aykroyd","Christopher Walken","John Travolta"],"question":"Which actor has featured in films including Rain Man and Kramer vs. Kramer?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"Albert Camus","incorrectAnswers":["François-René de Chateaubriand","Anatole France","Guy de Maupassant"],"question":"Which author wrote 'The Plague'?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"Blindness","incorrectAnswers":["Brideshead Revisited","The House of Mirth","Wise Blood"],"question":"Which book contains the character 'The Dog of Tears'?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Bern","incorrectAnswers":["Valencia","Athens","Oslo"],"question":"Which of these cities is in Switzerland?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"A Doe","incorrectAnswers":["A Jenny","A Soar","A Vixen"],"question":"What is a female rabbit known as?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"The Shining","incorrectAnswers":["Untouchable","Taxi Driver","Fargo"],"question":"Name the movie that matches the following plot summary: 'A family heads to a hotel for the winter where a sinister presence influences the father into violence.'","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"Michael Jackson","incorrectAnswers":["Nicki Minaj","Neil Young","Eric Clapton"],"question":"Which American singer released the song 'Bad'?","difficulty":"easy"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"Britney Spears","incorrectAnswers":["Madonna","Alanis Morissette","Nicki Minaj"],"question":"Which American singer, songwriter, dancer and actress released the song '...Baby One More Time'?","difficulty":"easy"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"Archimedes","incorrectAnswers":["Pythagoras","Euclid","Aristotle"],"question":"Who Famously Shouted 'Eureka!'?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"history","correctAnswer":"Cambria","incorrectAnswers":["Dunedin","Gaull","Merovingia"],"question":"What did the Romans call Wales?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"general_knowledge","correctAnswer":"Collywobbles","incorrectAnswers":["Frankenfood","Erf","Lackadaisical"],"question":"Which word is defined as 'a bellyache'?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"May Day","incorrectAnswers":["St. Patrick's Day","Easter Sunday","Christmas Day"],"question":"What is the name of the celebration to mark the beginning of summer, which sometimes includes dancing around a pole and giving baskets of flowers to friends and family?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"Britney Spears","incorrectAnswers":["Madonna","Alanis Morissette","Nicki Minaj"],"question":"Which American singer, songwriter, dancer and actress released the studio album 'Glory'?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"Contraction","incorrectAnswers":["Deflation","Capitalization","Quantative Easing"],"question":"What term in economics refers to a period where the economic output declines?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"sport_and_leisure","correctAnswer":"15","incorrectAnswers":["20","25","30"],"question":"How many red balls are there in a game of snooker?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"Chlorophyll","incorrectAnswers":["Nutrients","Grass","Oxygen"],"question":"What gives leaves their colour ?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"sport_and_leisure","correctAnswer":"John McEnroe","incorrectAnswers":["Pete Sampras","Bjorn Borg","Ivan Lendl"],"question":"Which tennis player was famous for the 'You cannot be serious'' outburst?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Guinea","incorrectAnswers":["Romania","Barbados","Lebanon"],"question":"Conakry is the capital city of which country?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"Trumpted","incorrectAnswers":["Bongo","Cello","Sitar"],"question":"Which of these is a brass instrument?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"history","correctAnswer":"Joan of Arc","incorrectAnswers":["Catherine the Great","Marie Antoinette","Cleopatra"],"question":"Which French teenager led the French troops that raised the Siege of Orleans during the Hundred Years' War?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"20 months","incorrectAnswers":["12 months","24 months","16 months"],"question":"What is the gestation period of an Asian Elephant? ","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"DH Lawrence","incorrectAnswers":["Samuel Scott","Walter Davis","Jane Austen"],"question":"Who wrote the novel \"Lady Chatterly's Lover\"?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"Doctor Faustus","incorrectAnswers":["Taming of the Shrew","Much Ado About Nothing","The Merchant of Venice"],"question":"Which of the following is not a play by William Shakespeare?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Cuba ","incorrectAnswers":["Jamaica","Trinidad","Barbados"],"question":"Which Is The Largest Island In The Caribbean?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"Epic","incorrectAnswers":["Genius of Love","Electric Avenue","96 Tears"],"question":"What song did Faith No More have a hit with in 1990?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"Aristotle","incorrectAnswers":["Thomas Hobbes","Ludwig Wittgenstein","Bertrand Russell"],"question":"Which philosopher famously said 'He who is unable to live in society, or who has no need because he is sufficient for himself, must be either a beast or a god'?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"Coldplay","incorrectAnswers":["Feeder","The Rolling Stones","U2"],"question":"In 1998 David Trimble & John Hume Joined Which Band On A Belfast Stage In Support Of The Good Friday Peace Agreement?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"Paris","incorrectAnswers":["London","New York","Rome"],"question":"According to Oscar Wilde, when good Americans die, they go to which world capital?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"history","correctAnswer":"President John F. Kennedy","incorrectAnswers":["Lee Harvey Oswald","John Lennon","Mahatma Gandhi"],"question":"Who was assassinated on November 22, 1963 in Dallas, Texas?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"J Robert Oppenheimer","incorrectAnswers":["Albert Einstein","Richard Feynman","Niels Bohr"],"question":"Who Was The First Director Of The Atomic Lab At Los Alamos New Mexico?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"The Beach Boys","incorrectAnswers":["Swans","Three 6 Mafia","The Velvet Underground"],"question":"Which band did Brian Wilson co-found?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"food_and_drink","correctAnswer":"Kuli Kuli","incorrectAnswers":["Kushari","Ambuyat","Ndolé"],"question":"Which of these dishes would you most expect to find in Benin?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"history","correctAnswer":"Britain","incorrectAnswers":["France","Germany","China"],"question":"What was the third country to get the atomic bomb?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"Bono","incorrectAnswers":["Chris Martin","Paul McCartney","Phil Collins"],"question":"On the Single “ Do They Know It's Christmas ” Only One Person Performed On Both The Original And The 20 Year Remake Band Aid 20, Who Was It?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"Woodwind","incorrectAnswers":["Stringed","Percussion","Brass"],"question":"What type of instrument is a flute?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"Spring","incorrectAnswers":["Winter","Summer","Fall"],"question":"Persephone was the Greek goddess of what?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Chile","incorrectAnswers":["Scotland","Tanzania","USA"],"question":"The territory of Easter Island belongs to which country?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"Toto","incorrectAnswers":["Styx","The Pussycat Dolls","Three 6 Mafia"],"question":"Which American rock band released the song 'Africa'?","difficulty":"easy"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"Slipknot","incorrectAnswers":["MercyMe","Three 6 Mafia","The Velvet Underground"],"question":"Which heavy metal band from the United States released the song 'Before I Forget'?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"The Lord of the Rings: The Fellowship of the Ring","incorrectAnswers":["Star Wars","Double Indemnity","Logan"],"question":"Name the movie that matches the following plot summary: 'A Hobbit and eight companions set out on a journey to destroy the powerful One Ring.'","difficulty":"easy"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"Beyoncé","incorrectAnswers":["Madonna","Drake","Nicki Minaj"],"question":"Which American singer, actress and record producer released the song 'Crazy in Love'?","difficulty":"easy"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"Charles Dickens","incorrectAnswers":["Oscar Wilde","Joseph Conrad","Henryk Sienkiewicz"],"question":"Which author wrote 'The Pickwick Papers'?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"New Zealand","incorrectAnswers":["Cambodia","Italy","Tanzania"],"question":"In which country would you find the Tongariro National Park?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"Humphrey Bogart","incorrectAnswers":["John Travolta","Peter O'Toole","Gregory Peck"],"question":"Which actor played the role of Rick Blaine in Casablanca?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"history","correctAnswer":"Auckland","incorrectAnswers":["Christchurch","Adelaide","Brisbane"],"question":"In the harbour of which city was the Greenpeace flagship Rainbow Warrior sunk in 1985?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Johannesburg","incorrectAnswers":["Algiers","Nairobi","Luanda"],"question":"Which of these cities is in South Africa?","difficulty":"easy"},{"category":"food_and_drink","correctAnswer":"Breakfast Cereals ","incorrectAnswers":["Bread","Crisps","Chewing Gum"],"question":"What Foodstuff Is The Most Advertised In The UK?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"Algae","incorrectAnswers":["Algeria","Alcohol","Algorithms"],"question":"What is Algology the study of?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"Heimdall","incorrectAnswers":["Vanir","Frigg","Odin"],"question":"Who is the Norse Watchman of the Gods?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"Hodie mihi, cras tibi","incorrectAnswers":["Cras es, noster","Tendit in, ardua virtus","Vincit, qui patitur"],"question":"Which of these Latin phrases translates to 'Today it's me, tomorrow it will be you'?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"general_knowledge","correctAnswer":"Anachronism","incorrectAnswers":["Calvinism","Cynicism","Feudalism"],"question":"Which -ism is used when something out of its proper historical context?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"Gary Oldman","incorrectAnswers":["James Franco","George Clooney","Laurence Fishburne"],"question":"Which actor played the role of James Gordon in the Dark Knight trilogy??","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Venice","incorrectAnswers":["Rome","Milan","Naples"],"question":"In which city would you find the Bridge of Sighs?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"food_and_drink","correctAnswer":"Mint Julep ","incorrectAnswers":["Mojito","Mint Daiqiri","Cosmopolitan"],"question":"Bourbon, sugar and mint make up which type of Cocktail?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"Subduction","incorrectAnswers":["Profession","Induction","Transgression"],"question":"What is the word used when one tectonic plate moves under another?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"\"Baby Got Back\" by Sir Mix-a-Lot","incorrectAnswers":["\"Bohemian Rhapsody\" by Queen","\"I'll Make a Man Out of You\" by Donny Osmond","\"Fergalicious\" by Fergie and will.i.am."],"question":"Which song begins with the lyrics: \"Oh my God, Becky, look at her butt!\"?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"Ionization","incorrectAnswers":["Electionification","Molecularization","Atomification"],"question":"What is the process by which an atom gains or loses charge by gaining or losing an electron?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"food_and_drink","correctAnswer":"Rice ","incorrectAnswers":["Maize","Wheat","Barley"],"question":"Which cereal is the only one grown standing in water?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"Washington, D.C.","incorrectAnswers":["New York City","Los Angeles","Chicago"],"question":"What city is the setting for the TV show 'Veep'?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Latvia","incorrectAnswers":["El Salvador","Papua New Guinea","Croatia"],"question":"Riga is the capital city of which country?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"Bob Dylan","incorrectAnswers":["Neil Young","Eric Clapton","Alanis Morissette"],"question":"Which American musician wrote the song 'All Along the Watchtower'?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"KitKat","incorrectAnswers":["Kelloggs Frosties","Red Lobster","McDonalds"],"question":"Which food brand is associated with the marketing slogan 'Have a break'?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"food_and_drink","correctAnswer":"The Middle East","incorrectAnswers":["China","Cameroon","Guyana"],"question":"Shawarma is a dish that is most associated with which part of the world?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"food_and_drink","correctAnswer":"Fermented Cabbage ","incorrectAnswers":["Spiced Sausage","Mashed Swede","Pickled Carrot"],"question":"What Is Sauerkraut?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"L. Frank Baum","incorrectAnswers":["Suzanne Collins","James Fenimore Cooper","Donna Leon"],"question":"Which author wrote 'The Wonderful Wizard of Oz'?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"The Birds","incorrectAnswers":["The Good, the Bad, and the Ugly","Sweet Smell of Success","The Manchurian Candidate"],"question":"Which film contains the character 'Melanie Daniels'?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"The Great Barrier Reef","incorrectAnswers":["The Big Blue Reef","The Sydney Reef","The Azure Fluid Reef"],"question":"What is the name of the famous large coral reef located off the coast of northeastern Australia?","difficulty":"easy"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"Nike","incorrectAnswers":["Reebok","Adidas","Puma"],"question":"Which brand is associated with the marketing slogan 'Just do it'?","difficulty":"easy"},{"category":"sport_and_leisure","correctAnswer":"The World Twenty20","incorrectAnswers":["The Daytona 500","The UCI World Championships","The Presidents Cup"],"question":"Which of these is a Cricket competition?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"Happy Days","incorrectAnswers":["Friends","The Big Bang Theory","The Simpsons"],"question":"'Joanie's First Kiss' and 'Richie Almost Dies' are episodes of which sitcom?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"Giulietta","incorrectAnswers":["Polo","Camry","Quattro"],"question":"Which of these is a model of car made by Alfa Romeo?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"Swarovski","incorrectAnswers":["Mustang","Ferrari","Bacardi"],"question":"Which of these brands has a swan on its logo?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"Die Hard","incorrectAnswers":["Lethal Weapon","The Terminator","RoboCop"],"question":"In what action film does a cop come to L.A. for Christmas and ends up killing a load of terrorists at his wife's work party?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"food_and_drink","correctAnswer":"Tubular pasta","incorrectAnswers":["Ribbon pasta","Shaped pasta","Soup pasta"],"question":"What type of pasta is calamarata?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"Argo","incorrectAnswers":["Amour","Beasts of the Southern Wild","Django Unchained"],"question":"Which film won the Academy Award for Best Picture in 2012?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"general_knowledge","correctAnswer":"Jentacular","incorrectAnswers":["Quire","Ulotrichous","Meldrop"],"question":"Which word is defined as 'pertaining to breakfast'?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"Henryk Sienkiewicz","incorrectAnswers":["Leo Tolstoy","Ivan Turgenev","Charles Dickens"],"question":"Which author wrote 'The Knights of the Cross'?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"Sri Lanka","incorrectAnswers":["Uganda","Taiwan","Algeria"],"question":"Tamil is a language spoken in which of these countries?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Turkey","incorrectAnswers":["England","Germany","Hungary"],"question":"In which country would you find the UNESCO World Heritage site of Pergamon?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"Sulfur","incorrectAnswers":["Hydrogen","Chlorine","Gold"],"question":"What chemical element is brimstone synonymous with?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"Sikhism","incorrectAnswers":["Buddhism","Judaism","Hinduism"],"question":"What religion was founded by Guru Nanak ?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"Quran","incorrectAnswers":["Torah","Dead Sea Scrolls","Bolah"],"question":"What is the holy book of Islam?","difficulty":"easy"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"All About Eve","incorrectAnswers":["Apocalypse Now","The Good, the Bad, and the Ugly","Citizen Kane"],"question":"Which film contains the character 'Margo Channing'?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"Artemis","incorrectAnswers":["Apollo","Aphrodite","Athena"],"question":"Who is the Greek equivalent of the Roman god Diana?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"Musical instruments","incorrectAnswers":["Stars","Embryos","The heart"],"question":"What is Organology the study of?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"France","incorrectAnswers":["Monaco","Algeria","Belgium"],"question":"Which of these countries borders Spain?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"history","correctAnswer":"Charles I","incorrectAnswers":["Louis XIV","Louis XVI","Charles III"],"question":"Which King Wore Two Shirts At His Execution So As Not To Shiver And Appear Frightened?","difficulty":"hard"},